White House Tapes: Conversation 948-012, July 11, 1973
National Archives and Records Administration
- Connally left at 4:22 pm.
Access is governed by the Presidential Recordings and Materials Preservation Act of 1974 (PRMPA); Nixon Public Access Regulations 36 CFR 1275 of the NARA Code of Federal Regulations, including the 1996 Tapes Settlement Agreement (Appendix A); and protocols related to classified national security information, including Executive Order 13526.
For more information, please contact the Tapes Team at the Richard Nixon Presidential Library and Museum: nixon@nara.gov or (301) 837-3290.
Acquisitions Information
Presidential Recordings and Materials Preservation Act of 1974
The Nixon-era White House Tapes are subject to the Presidential Recordings and Materials Preservation Act of 1974 (PRMPA). PRMPA, which applies only to the Nixon Presidential Materials, stipulates that those materials relevant to the understanding of Abuse of Governmental Power and Watergate are to be processed and released to the public prior to the release of all other materials. Materials related to the Abuse of Governmental Power and the constitutional and statutory duties of the President and his White House staff are retained by the National Archives. PRMPA mandated the promulgation of access restrictions for the processing of the Nixon Tapes.
The resulting Nixon Public Acccess Regulations 36 CFR 1275 state that the National Archives must segregate and return to the estate of former President Nixon those materials identified as purely "personal-private" or "personal-political," and unrelated to the President's constitutional and statutory duties. This conversation has been processed under these regulations.
2007 Deed of Gift
However, in 2007, the estate of Richard Nixon negotiated a Deed of Gift with the Richard Nixon Presidential Library and Museum. By this agreement, materials deemed "personal-political" have been deeded back to the National Archives for release to the public. Materials originally deemed "person-private" have been deeded back to the National Archives, with the exception of materials concerning the medical history or non-Watergate-related personal finances of Richard Nixon or the non-public activities of the First Family.
This conversation has been re-reviewed under the provisions of the 2007 Deed of Gift between the estate of Richard Nixon and the National Archives. Changes in access have been noted.
Description, encoding, and public access to the White House Tapes subject logs are supported by a partnership between the Richard Nixon Presidential Library and Museum and the Office of Innovation at the National Archives and Records Administration.
Digitization of the White House Tapes and related activities by the Richard Nixon Presidential Library and Museum are supported by the Preservation Programs Division and the Office of Innovation at the National Archives and Records Administration.
Encoded by Amanda T. Ross, January 15, 2016
Edited by Amanda T. Ross, June 2016